情况并不乐观  理查德 3
It doesn't look good, Richard. 4
事实上跟你说实话  情况很严重 8
In fact, to be quite frank, it looks pretty bad.9
我就不拐弯抹角了 13
Rather than beat around the bush, 14
跟你说实话吧 18
I'm just gonna come right out and say it. 19
理查德  你患了肺癌  已经到了四期
Richard, you have stage four lung cancer.
一直困扰你的上背部疼痛
The pain you've been experiencing in your upper back
其实是你肺部的恶性肿瘤造成的
is actually the result of malignant tumors within your lungs,
根据这点来看  你已经患癌很长一段时间了
which it sadly appears you have for some time.
现在查出来已经有点晚了
As we're catching this late in the game,
你的癌细胞仍有可能会扩散
your cancer has also had the opportunity to spread
尤其是扩散到你的脊柱和肾上腺
specifically to your spine, and adrenals.
你得通知你的学校
You wanna put in notice with the college.
通知维罗妮卡和你的女儿
You should notify Veronica and your daughter
越快越好  因为治疗刻不容缓
as soon as possible as treatment will begin immediately.
还有多长时间
How long are we talking?
如果治疗的话  一年
With treatment, a year,
如果幸运的话  一年半
a year and a half, if you're lucky.
不治疗呢
And without?
也许能有六个月
Probably six months.
我很抱歉  理查德
I am so sorry, Richard.
教授
null1
操
Fuck.
美国部分大学实行学季制  即一学年分为四学季
null1
让我们一起把这个学季变得更精彩
So let's make this a fantastic quarter.
拿到我们迫切需要的那点额外资助
We get that extra little bit of funding that we so desperately need.
还有问题吗
Uh, any questions?
操
Fuck.
什么  好了
What...? Uhm... Okay.
操
Fuck.
去他妈的耶稣
Jesus fucking Jesus.
耶稣  上帝  操
Jesus. God. Fuck.
去他妈的
Fucking bastard!
操  耶稣
Fuck! Jesus!
去他妈的
Fuck it, huh?
去他妈的上帝
Fucking God!
去你妈的
Fuck you!
Fuck you.
操
Fuck.
第一章
我有事要说
接下来是要让无神论者祈祷了吗
Shall the atheist say grace then?
闭嘴  理查德
Shut up, Richard.
好的  亲爱的
Of course, my dear.
其实我也有事要说
I actually have something I wanna say.
来吧  孩子  你要说什么
Go ahead, kid. What do you got?
我想让你们知道  我是个同性恋
I wanted you to know that I'm gay.
你在说什么
What on Earth?
天哪
Jesus Christ.
奥丽维娅  我还以为你要说什么坏消息
Olivia, I thought it was something bad.
不  你不是  奥丽芙
No, you're not, Olive.
你说我不是是什么意思
What do you mean I'm not?
你不是同性恋  不是拉拉
You're not gay. I mean, you're not a lesbian.
我是
Yeah, I am.
我觉得我知道自己的性取向
Yeah. No, I think I'd know my own sexual preference.
这只是阶段性的
Uh, it's just a phase.
就我个人而言  我觉得这挺好的
I, for one, think it's fantastic.
不要惯着她
Don't placate her.
我没有惯着我的女儿
I'm not placating my daughter.
你怎么能这样否认我
How dare you deny me like this.
我没有否认你  亲爱的
I'm not denying you, sweetheart.
我只是不认同你做这样的事
I'm just denying your call for attention
来吸引注意力  仅此而已
or whatever else this is. That's all.
我了解你  奥丽芙  比你自己更了解你
I know you, Olive, better than you know yourself.
不  妈妈  你一点都不了解我
No, mother. You know no shit about me.
奥丽维娅  拜托你回来  奥丽维娅
Olivia, please come back, sweetheart. Olivia.
随她去吧
Let her go.
你教育孩子的方法
Your finesse of parenting...
一直都让我叹为观止
has always amazed me.
我也有事要说
I also have something I'd like to say.
洗耳恭听
I can't wait.
我出轨了
I'm having an affair.
我出轨了  我觉得应该让你知道
I'm having an affair and I thought you should know.
你为什么觉得应该让我知道
And why did you think I should know?
因为是跟亨利
Because it's with Henry.
哪个亨利
Henry who?
亨利·莱特
Henry Wright.
Henry Wright?
我的上司
My boss?
别吧  维罗妮卡  这也恶心了
No, no, no, no. Veronica. That's real revolting.
你疯了吗  拜托
Are you out of your mind? Come on.
就算是搞外遇也要有点品位吧
At least have a little bit of taste in your infidelity.
选择权在你
It's up to you,
但如果是我  我会选救生员或水管工
but I'd fucked a pool boy myself or a plumber.
而不是跟一个没种的软蛋
Than had some fucking nutless sack.
我可以跟你保证不是软的
I assure you it's not empty.
什么
What?
亨利有幸比常人多一个睾丸
Henry has been blessed with a spare testicle.
Henry was blessed with a spare testicle?
你确定那不是囊肿或者癌性肿瘤
Are you sure it's not a cyst or a cancerous growth?
你真的在乎吗
Do you even care?
关于他的第三个蛋
About his third nut?
不  我不在乎
No. No, I don't.
就我所知
As far as I'm concerned,
他的那些房产早就失去了投资价值
that real estate's lost its value long ago.
你真是个混蛋
You're such an ass.
我承认
Self-admitted.
为我们神圣的婚姻干杯
So let us drink to our holy matrimony.
你自己喝去吧
Drink by yourself.
这个主意更好
Much better idea.
你之前想跟我们说什么来着
Ugh. What was it you wanted to tell us?
我恐怕  把牛排煎过头了  就这事
I was, uh, afraid I overcooked the steaks. That's it.
真是个混蛋
Such an asshole.
但是她根本不是这个意思
No, but that's not what she's saying at all.
她为整个女权运动打下了基础
She's laying the groundwork for the whole feminist movement.
继续
Go on.
她的思想比同代人前卫一百多年
Like a hundred years in advance and...
怎么回事
What was that?
你不打算做点什么吗
Aren't you gonna do anything?
比如什么
Like what?
我也不知道  叫人来处理
I don't know. Call someone.
你是它朋友吗
Were you friends with it?
还是你认识它  知道它的名字
Did you know it personally, by, like, by name?
就是只鸟而已
It's a fucking bird.
我不知道该叫谁来
I don't know who to call.
-我能继续说吗  -不能
- Can I continue? - No, you may not.
是谁的手机  是你的手机吗
Oh, whose phone is it? Is that your phone?
靠
Shit.
在那儿呢  她的
There we go. Here she is.
抱歉
Sorry.
是我的  抱歉
Mine. Sorry.
我以为自己调成震动了  但是
Um, I thought it was on vibrate but it's...
不  不  没关系  接电话吧
No, no, no, please, take your call.
站起来接电话
Stand up and take your call.
请  不要害羞
Please. Don't be shy.
站起来  然后接电话
Stand up and take your call.
你好
Hello.
我一会给你回电话  因为我在上课
I'm gonna call you back actually because I'm in class.
不  我就在课堂上
No, as in I'm in class.
现在  我正站在课堂上
Right now. I'm standing up.
我知道这很奇怪  好了
I know it's weird. Okay.
再见  拜  拜
Goodbye. Bye. Bye.
非常好
Fascinating.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不要抱歉
Oh, don't be.
好了
Okay.
从现在开始
From here on out,
我们要采取非常不同的上课方式
we're gonna do things very, very differently.
所以  那些完全没兴趣
So for those of you who are not even remotely interested
坐在这里的人  请你们离开
in being here, please leave.
很简单  只要走出这扇门
Just simply walk out the door
你就自动得到一个C
and you'll receive an automatic C.
我已经没多少时间可以浪费了
I no longer have time to be wasted
我也不想浪费你们的
nor do I intend on wasting yours.
所以  那些得过C
So for those of you who receive grades of,
或更低成绩的人  就主动点
say, a C or worse, let's just be proactive.
收拾好东西  现在就赶紧走人
Pack up your shit. And vamos now.
很好  这就对了
Good. Here we go.
你们之中如果有人打算以后去学商科
If any of you have any intentions of studying business,
现在就给我滚出去
get the fuck out now.
我只说这一遍
I'm not gonna say it again.
如果你们低下头正好看到自己穿的是运动裤
If you look down and you happen to find yourself in sweatpants
或是任何有抽绳之类的裤子
or rather pants with the drawstring or something,
-慢走不送  -什么
- just please leave. - What?
最重要的一点  如果你们从未
Most important of all, if you've never read a book
出于内心的愉悦去阅读一本书
for our own internal pleasure...
那你们就不属于这里  出去
you don't belong here. Get out.
如果你们之中有人
If any of you find yourself
属于以上类别之一
falling into any of these categories,
我向你们保证  你们的成绩不会高于C
I assure you, you will not do better than a C.
这就对了
Here we go.
政府公务员和政客都走了
The government workers and the politicians included.
运动裤那段话不是开玩笑
The, uh, sweatpants comment is not a joke.
我生病了  我感冒了
I'm sick. I have a cold.
好了  现在  那些有兴趣
Right. Now, for those of you who are interested
向伟大的灵魂学习的人
in learning from greater minds,
那么请你们这学季读一本书
and there are today, you're in charge of reading one book
只读这一本
and one book only to this quarter.
读完之后  你就站在讲台上
After doing so, you will then stand up here
自己来讲一堂课
and you will run a class of your own.
很好  只动嘴不动手的也走了
Excellent. There go the kings and queens of the water cooler,
未来的企业蛀虫
corporate whores of tomorrow.
C  还是算了吧
C. Maybe not.
然后你们就请站上讲台  告诉同学们
And then you will stand up here and you'll persuade your peers
这本书的重要性
of the work's importance.
做到这一点  你们就能得B
For that, you'll receive a B.
如果你教了我们新知识  就能得A
If you teach us something new, you receive an A.
还有什么问题吗
Any questions?
对了  还有一件事
Ah-ha. Yes. One more thing.
不要宣扬女权或是同性恋
No feminist or queer propaganda.
说真的  邋遢凌乱的女人们面对的困境
The plight of unkempt women is truly the last thing
是我现在最不想知道的东西
I would like to think about right now.
我认为你无权这么做
I don't think you can do that.
我就这么做了
I just did.
现在  我要在接下来的72小时里放飞自我
And now, I shall embark on an emotional...bender for 72 hours.
我多半会独自饮酒
Most likely, I'll be drinking alone
而我对此感觉良好
and I'm all right with that.
所以本节课就取消了
So as a result, class is cancelled.
我说完了
That's it.
下课
Class dismissed.
对了如果你们有人卖大麻
Oh, yeah, by the way, if any of you sell marijuana
或是认识卖大麻的人
or you know anyone who does,
请在办公时间来找我
would you please visit me during office hours?
谢了  拜
Thanks. Bye.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
美国大学中工作一定年限的教师享有的带薪假期
null
下学季我想要个学术休假
I need to go on sabbatical next quarter.
不行  我没法给你批学术休假  这要一年
I would... No, I can't give you a sabbatical, it takes a year.
要花一年的时间才能批下来
A year to get that kind of thing done.
那你就得做点什么来加速批准了
You're gonna have to do something to speed it up.
不  我不行
No, I can't.
你要学术休假干什么
What do you want to go on a sabbatical for?
我想写出下一部伟大的美国长篇小说
I would like to write the next great American novel.
-是吗  -或者短篇小说
- Oh, yeah? - Or novela,
-取决于故事长短  -书是关于什么的
- depending on the length. - What's it about?
讲的是一个孤儿的故事
It's gonna be about an orphan
她养了一群大兔子或者小兔子
who raises rabbits or bunnies around there.
那书名是什么
And what's it called?
目前暂定的题目是《找到快乐的巴妮》
Right now, the tentative title is Bunny Fun Found
因为她的名字叫做巴妮  奇怪的是
because her name is Bunny and oddly enough,
-她很快乐  -满口屁话
- she was having fun... - You're full of shit.
满口屁话  你在骗我
You're full of shit. You're having me on.
-我得了癌症  彼得  -什么
- I have cancer, Peter. - What?
我得了癌症  而且情况并不乐观
I have cancer and it doesn't get look good.
我的老天  理查德
Jesus Christ, Richard.
我不想死在这里
I don't want to die here.
我不想像这样死在这里
I don't wanna die here like this.
拜托让我走吧  就让我独自死去
Please get me out. Just let me die alone.
让我安息
Let me die in peace.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
不要在桌上握我的手
No hands above the table.
好的
Okay.
是什么类型的癌症
What kind of cancer is it?
是肺癌
It's, uh, it's lung cancer.
你又不抽烟
You don't smoke.
我是不抽  但现在可以了
No. I can now.
听着  凡人皆有一死
Listen, this is what happens to everybody.
我们所有人都会面对死亡
It's what happens to all of us.
你也有可能也会得这种病
I mean, you could be ridden with the same damn thing.
你为什么要对我说这种话
Why would you say something like that to me, huh?
不是  我是在讲这个道理
No, no. I'm making a point.
抱歉  方式有误
I'm sorry. It came out wrong.
-对不起  对不起  -没事的
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - That's all right.
我真心讨厌这些娘娘腔的玻璃酒杯
I really hate these effeminate glasses.
我们要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我会把我的药柜装满
I'm gonna fill my medicine cabinet.
然后在路上解决
And... I'm gonna ride this thing out.
等等  你不打算接受治疗吗
Wait, you're not gonna get treatments?
不
No.
-你欠我的  彼得  -是的
- You owe me, Peter. - Uh, yes.
是的  是的  当然
Yes. Yes, of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在你可以放开我的手了
You can let go of my hands now
然后我们或许可以干一杯
and then we can have a drink maybe.
-好的  -谢谢
- Yeah. - Thank you.
那么  敬时日无多
So to the months end.
祝你身体早日康复
To your health.
这时候就别开玩笑了吧
There's no need to be facetious.
我没想开玩笑
I didn't mean to be facetious.
也别张着大嘴到处讲
And don't go blabbering your little wet mouth about this.
-我不会说的  -这与任何人都无关
- No, no. - This is no one's business
-这是我自己的事  -当然
- but my own - Of course.
我觉得你的作品
I think your art is
精妙绝伦  匠心独具
brilliant, stunning,
是非常好的投资
and a wonderful investment.
事实上
In fact...
你能把整个学校都重设计一遍吗
could you do the whole campus?
-凭你的天赋  这当然  -佛罗里达学院
- Certainly with your talent... - To the College of Florida?
那是我的事
That's my responsibility.
不用你操心这个
You don't need to worry about that.
敬你最新的外遇
To your latest infidelity.
敬你的荣誉绿帽
And your honorable cuckolding.
那是什么
Ooh, what's that?
这是一颗白色的椭圆形药丸
It's a white oblong pill.
你从哪搞到的
Where did you get it?
我们是富裕的美国上层社会中年白人
We're well-to-do middle-aged WASPs.
我们什么药的处方都能搞到  亲爱的
We can get prescriptions for anything we want, darling.
好了
Okay.
如果你好好表现
If you behave yourself...
我就再给你一颗蓝色的三角形药丸
I'll give you a blue triangular one next.
我听说你可喜欢它们了
I heard you're quite fond of them.
说正事
Onto serious matters.
-说吧  -你心里清楚
- Go for it. - And you know at heart,
我根本不在乎你和亨利的事
I don't give a damn about you and Henry.
你怎么高兴怎么来
You do whatever you please.
但是你要意识到
But you have to realize
从现在开始  我也要活得自由
that from here on out, I'll be living just as freely.
我已经在我们悲剧的婚姻中
I've played a rather quiet role
沉默了好久了
in the tragedy that is our marriage.
而且
and...
说实话  我受够了
quite frankly, I'm done.
是时候让我们回归到
It's time that we lived a bit closer to the...
最初的本质上了
primal truth of it all.
所以从现在开始  我们想上谁就上谁
So from this point on, let us fuck who we wanna fuck.
想磕什么就磕什么
Let us ingest what we wanna ingest.
总之  只要我们高兴就好
And all in all, just do whatever the hell we damn well please.
说得好
Here, here.
只有一个要求
One request,
乐子与生活分开
that we do so discretely.
我们至少不要让这段破碎的婚姻
Let us at least attempt to keep the parental damage
对我们可爱的拉拉女儿造成太多伤害
to our sweet lesbian love child to a minimum.
完全同意
I wholeheartedly agree.
太好了  那问题就解决了
Wonderful. And the matter is settled.
理查德
Richard?
怎么了  亲爱的
Yes, dear?
我能问问你的家伙还好使吗
Dare I ask if your equipment still works?
我不知道
I don't know.
很遗憾  它已经很久没派上用场了
I mean, sadly, it's laid dormant for years.
即便不好使  再开一种药就行了
But if it doesn't, it's just one more prescription to fill.
这杯敬  我们的新生
Here's to, uh, our new lives.
还有你新获的自由
And your new freedoms.
现在把小蓝片给我吧  我已经表现得很好了
Now, hand over a blue one I've behaved myself admirably.
他就像是那种
He was like this, um...
爱上自己表妹的17世纪诗人
17th century poet who fell in love with his cousin and...
-爱上自己的表妹  -该死
- ...fell in love with his cousin? - Oh, shit.
你真是个混蛋
You're such an asshole.
-怎么了  -我父母在家
- What? - My parents are home.
没关系
Hey. It's okay.
你能保证不评判我吗
Can you promise not to judge me?
不用担心  真的
Don't worry, seriously.
摔坏了
It's broken.
彻底坏掉了
I mean, the whole thing is broken.
奥丽维娅  看  亲爱的
Oh, Olivia. Look, dear.
-是奥丽维娅和小伙伴  -怎么了
- It's Olivia and company. - What's going on?
你妈妈把台灯打坏了
Uh, your mom broke the lamp.
你们没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  亲爱的  当然了  怎么会有事
Yes, darling. Of course, why wouldn't we be?
因为你们看上去像是喝多了或是嗑药了
Because you seem like you're drunk or on drugs.
无可否认  我们两者皆有
Admittedly, we are on a bit of both.
但别让这事影响了你的决定
But don't let that influence your decisions.
别听他的
Oh, don't listen to him.
都是正规处方药
They're just prescriptions.
我是维罗妮卡  奥利维娅的妈妈
I'm Veronica, Olivia's mother.
你好  我是泰勒
Hi, I'm Taylor.
很高兴认识你
Oh, nice to meet you...
不好意思
Excuse me.
小心  亲爱的  别用力过度
Careful, dear. Let's not exert yourself.
所以这位...她就是...
So is this... is she...
泰勒就是泰勒  妈妈
Taylor is Taylor, mother.
当然  当然  那是一定的
Yes, yes, of course, you are.
对了  我是理查德
And by the way, I'm Richard.
-你要喝一杯吗  -对  来喝点
- Would you like a drink? - Yes, please, come.
-跟我们一起喝一杯  -不  等等  不
- Join us for a drink. - No, hang on. No.
你们太吓人了  我们要走了
You're being very creepy. We're going.
-吓人  -是的
- Creepy? - Yes.
我们只是找点乐子
We're just having fun.
走吧
Come on.
那个  很高兴认识你们
Hey, well, it was very nice meeting you.
-再见  -很高兴认识你
- Bye. - Nice to meet you.
还算愉快
That was pleasant.
你觉得刚才我们表现得怎么样
So how do you think that went?
从一到十打分的话
On a scale of one to ten,
我打四分
I'd say a four.
同意
Agreed.
我只对自己稍微有点失望
I'm only mildly disappointed in myself.
我觉得很丢人  是的
I feel ashamed. Yeah.
我们之间是怎么回事  理查德
What happened to us, Richard?
我们之间是怎么回事
What happened to us?
生活
Life.
即便我能回到过去
You know, if I could go back in time,
我也还是不知道该弥补什么
I don't even know what it is I'm supposed to fix.
我倒是能轻易想到许多事情
Oh, I could readily think of many things.
我没问你
I didn't ask you.
是的
True.
你是要把所有结婚礼物都打碎吗
You're gonna break all our wedding presents.
你有没有注意到它们都是空心的
Did you ever notice that they're all hollow?
这话什么意思
Ah, what does that mean?
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
理查德
Richard?
怎么了  亲爱的
Yes, dear?
谢谢你帮我
Thank you for helping me.
不客气
Of course.
给你梳头发一直都是
Holding your hair back has always been
我此生最大的荣幸之一
one of my life's great honors.
我认真的
I'm serious.
我也是
In ways, so am I.
你觉得奥利维娅恨我吗
Do you think Olivia hates me?
是的
Yes.
但她也该恨
But she's supposed to.
我不是个坏人
I'm not a bad person.
我知道你不是  维罗妮卡
I know you're not, Veronica.
没人说过你是
No one ever said you were.
第二章
搞  好好搞
你们还算是
Well, you are a...
一群比较讨人喜欢的孩子
relatively attractive group of kids.
我看到了几个小下巴
I mean, I see a few weak chins here and there.
不过  我猜很可能是因为
But, uh, I think that's probably just due to
一些优秀的新英格兰式家庭教育
some fine New England breeding. Hmm?
漂亮的母亲  富有的父亲
Beautiful mother, rich father,
寒冷的冬季  之类的
cold winter, that kind of thing.
你抽烟吗
Do you smoke?
不抽
No.
你看起来像会抽烟
You look like you do.
我抽  布朗先生
I do, Mr. Brown.
能给我来一根吗
Would you mind if I have one?
当然可以
No, not at all.
所以...
So, um...
咱们轮流自我介绍吧
let's go through and introduce ourselves.
有主动的吗
Any volunteers?
那我先来  我叫理查德
I'll go first. My name is Richard.
我是你们的教授  点上
I'm your professor. Go ahead.
这也太他妈呛人了
That was fucking wretched.
天啊
Jesus.
好吧
Okay.
下一个谁来
Who's next?
就你吧
How about you?
-我  -对  你
- Me? - Yeah, you,
带手机的姑娘
girl with the phone.
你是谁
Who are you,
我们为什么要认识你
why should we know you,
你以后想做什么
what do you want to do with your life?
好的
Okay.
我叫克莱尔
I'm Claire.
我来自纽约上州
I'm from Upstate New York.
你们为什么要认识我
Why you should know me?
我也不知道
I don't know.
是的  我不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
我猜大概是因为我叔叔是学校校长
I guess because my uncle is the president of the school.
亨利·莱特是你叔叔
Henry Wright is your uncle?
-是的  -我最讨厌那个混蛋了
- Yes. - I can't stand the fuck.
我也不太喜欢他
I don't really like him either.
那太好了
That's very good to hear.
他就像那种桃子冰淇淋一样
I mean, he's so peach melba.
又腻又...
Just slimy and...
我有个主意
I've got an idea.
不如我们先把自我介绍暂停一下
How about we put a little pause to this shit
找个酒吧
and we go down to the bar,
在那里继续怎么样
and we can run over it there.
我的生父其实是在波士顿一个堆肥大会上
My biological father actually met my mothers
认识我妈妈的
at a monthly compost meeting in Boston.
他是一个社会人类学家...
He's this social anthropologist over at a...
好了  萝丝
Okay. Rose,
去给我们每人再多拿两杯酒  好吗
go and grab two more pitchers for everybody, would you?
你为什么不直接记账呢
Why don't you just put them in your tab?
那就没意义了
No, that's not the point.
我想要你去拿
See, I want you to go and get them.
而且我想要你现在就去拿  好吗
And I want you go and get them now, please?
我能再拿点鹰嘴豆泥吗
Can I get some hummus?
当然  拿吧
Yeah, get some hummus.
谢谢
Thank you.
我给你们所有人一个建议
Let me give you all a piece of advice.
一定要离那种有意怀孕的人远点儿
Steer very clear of anyone who has even the faintest,
有一丁点想法都不行
slightest whip of intentional conception.
我爸妈就是有意要的我
I was conceived intentionally.
告诉我你的名字
Well, I need to know your name.
对了  希望你们爸妈都告诉你们了
By the way, I hope your parents all told you
你们最终都他妈会死
that you fucking die at the end.
你会死  你会死
You're gonna die. You're gonna die.
你也会死  有一天
You're gonna die. One day,
我们幸福的小萝丝也会死
even our blessed little Rose will die.
所以  我一直在想
So, what I'm wondering is, why the fuck
为什么我们要浑浑噩噩地度过这一生
do we sort of float through this weird thing
却不曾真正地活着
called life without living?
懂吗  生活
You know, live.
不要生存  不要只是生存
Don't exist. Don't simply exist.
那也太他妈无趣了  而是真正的生活
That's boring as fuck. Live.
多趟几趟浑水  多搞砸些事儿
You know. Stir some shit up. Fuck some shit up.
好好搞
Fuck it right.
我更关心的是
What I wanna focus on
如何丰富我们的生活
is enriching our lives.
然后从中提取某种
And try to extract some sort of wisdom
能值得铭记一生的智慧
that we can carry with us.
而不是妈咪和爸比的陈词滥调
You know, something other than mommy and daddy's baggage.
上帝保佑你  亲爱的
Ah, bless you, dear.
我想对你眨眼  但是我一直都学不会
You know, I'd wink at you but I never learned how.
就是想告诉你一声
So I just thought you should know it.
有人还想要别的吗
Anybody want anything else?
我能来杯威士忌吗
Yeah, could I get a whiskey?
可以
Oh, that's fine.
她对我眨眼了
She winked at me.
我拿到鹰嘴土豆泥了
I got the hummus, so...
圣诞节得救了
Christmas is saved.
天哪
My God.
来
Here we go.
希望我们永远铭记
May we forever remember
每一分每一秒
that in each and every moment,
我们都在书写自己人生的故事
we are composing the stories of our lives.
我们要努力让这个故事变得有意义
Let's aim to make it a meaningful read
至少得有趣  好吗
or at least, an interesting one, yeah?
好了  干杯
All right. Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
现在我要失陪一下
Now, if you will excuse me,
去探索搞外遇的乐趣了
I intend to explore a smidgen of infidelity.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
好了  孩子们  玩得开心
All right, kids. Have fun.
School is Over by The Bell Sisiters
null
对不起
I'm so sorry.
-闭嘴上我  -好
- Just fuck me. - Okay.
你什么决定都不用做
You don't have to make any choices at all.
我们全部包办  我们可以翻新科学礼堂
We can cover it all. We could renovate science hall.
我们可以给英文系换一位新主任
We could bring in a new chair to the English department.
我说  "当然  那还用说吗"
Well, I said, "Well, of course, that goes without saying."
当然了  你的大学...
Surely you have better...
排名比我高
you know, college rankings than I.
闭嘴
Shut up.
天哪  维罗妮卡  你这是干什么
Jesus, Veronica. What the hell was that?
滚开
Fuck off.
让他们看
Let them watch.
Angel of Mine by Nick Landers
null
萝丝  闭上嘴
Rose, close your mouth.
你这么张着嘴不好看
It's unattractive when you gape like that.
丹尼仔  帮我个忙
Danny boy, do me a favor.
等你们散伙时把账结了
Uh, close out the tab when you're done.
-好的  -还有那个...
- Yeah. - And what... what...
不好意思  你叫什么来着  甜心
I'm sorry, what's your name again, sweetheart?
莎拉
Sarah.
一定记得给莎拉一份丰厚的小费
Be sure and leave Sarah a healthy tip
因为她是个特别  特别好的人
because it turns out she's a very, very nice person.
我们下周再见  好吗
I'll see you guys next week, yeah?
对了  萝丝  你第一个讲
Oh, yeah, Rose. Let me get you out of the way first.
-好好准备  -但我不知道讲什么
- So be prepared. - But I don't know what to do.
19世纪美国小说家赫尔曼·梅尔维尔所著的长篇小说
null
《白鲸》  那就《白鲸》吧
Moby Dick. Moby Dick it is.
好主意  好的
Good idea. All right.
玩得开心
Have a good one.
他不到一分钟就勾搭上了那个女服务生
He just picked up that waitress in less than a minute.
还在卫生间里搞上了
And fucked her in the bathroom.
他们都是有自主意识的成年人
Yeah, well, they're both consenting adults,
所以他们想做什么都行
so they can do whatever they want.
为这个干一杯
Cheers to that.
Flat Bed Rhythm By Al Hazan
null
吉宝  吉宝  吉宝  看
Jibbles, Jibbles, Jibbles, look.
看  我觉得妈妈正在偷腥呢
Look, I feel mommy is cheating.
汽车旅馆
null
写的什么
What's it say?
好使
It works.
我们一起去劝他
Let's go try to stop him
-别喝那么多酒  -行了  彼得
- from drinking so much. - Oh. Peter, come on.
他正享受着呢
He's having a good time.
理查德  你看上去精神焕发啊
Ah, Richard, you're looking rather sprite.
我刚刚不戴套搞了一发
Oh, I just had unprotected sex.
和谁
Oh, with who?
狮子酒吧一个特甜的姑娘  你好  唐纳
Some very sweet girl from the Lion's Pub. Hello, Donna.
好恶心  他告诉我们这个干嘛
Oh, that's disgusting. Why would he tell us that?
你今天过得如何  宝贝
So, how was your day, sweetheart?
还行
Fine.
好  还行就行
Good. Fine's fine.
-泰勒怎么样  -她还行
- How's Taylor? - She's fine.
那就更行了
That's even finer.
让我们为这还行的一天干杯
Let us cheers to a fine day all round.
你们好
Hello.
维罗妮卡
Hmm, Veronica.
坐下
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're so welcome.
现在  我们重新来一次  好吗
Now, let's give this another shot, shall we?
奥利维娅  你妈妈想向你道歉
Olivia, your mother would like to apologize.
是  我想为了我那天晚上的言行
Yes, I would like to apologize...
向你道歉
for my behavior the other night.
我不知道为什么我的反应会那么
I don't know why my reaction was so, um...
怎么说
I don't know.
右翼
Right wing?
是
Yes.
我很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
很好
Beautiful.
奥利维娅  你接受你妈妈的道歉吗
Olivia, do you accept your mother's apology?
接受
Sure.
好了
Well, good.
事情解决了
The matter's settled.
好好享用
Bon appetit.
以实玛利声称  环球旅行
So, Ishmael claims that a journey around the world
就是把你带回到你开始的地方
just brings you back to where you were before you started,
但事实上这句话来自一个失去一切的男人
but this is actually coming from a man, who's lost everything
也就是他的整个现实世界和意识
that's been his entire reality and consciousness
在过去的几年里
for the past few years...
我的脸看起来晒黑了吗
Do I look like I'm getting some color?
我不知道  在室外不好说
I don't know. Hard to tell from here.
我真的感觉晒黑了一点
It really feels like I'm getting some color.
有人有问题吗
Does anyone have any questions?
什么  有
What? Oh, uh, yes. Um...
一个词概括
In a word?
复仇
Vengeance.
所以你喜欢这本书
So, you liked it?
没错  我喜欢
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
但这本书里却没有肩宽阔背的悲伤女人
And yet, there were no broad shouldered women lamenting,
在二楼的窗户边抽泣  对吗
and sobbing out of second story windows, were there?
-没有  -很好
- No. - Good.
这就意味着我们正在打破
That means we're breaking down
你的合作人格
that co-op personality of yours.
我觉得这个学季结束前
I think we're probably gonna
我们甚至能在你身上打磨出一点锋芒
get a bit of an edge out of you before the end of the quarter.
什么
Excuse me?
你得了A-
You get an A minus.
这成绩又不坏
That's not a bad thing.
稍等一下  同学们
Just give me one second, kids.
我要再去看一眼
I'm gonna have to take one more look
那个即将诞生的艺术品
at this artistic still born.
快看  天哪
Look at it, Jesus Christ,
是个鸡巴
it's a boner.
那就是个竖起来的大鸡巴
That is a gigantic boner.
-亲爱的  -那不是你老婆的作品吗
- Hi, honey. - Isn't that your wife's work?
对  没错
Yeah, it is. It is.
但那并不代表我就不能评判它
It doesn't mean I don't have an opinion on the matter.
Take Me for What I Am By Henry Ford
null
谁啊
Who is it?
丹尼尔·莱特
Uh, it's Daniel Wright.
进来吧
Come on in.
这歌不错
Nice music.
还以为你会听别的歌
Thought you'd be listening something different.
真的吗  比如什么
Really, like what exactly?
不知道  巴迪·霍利的
I don't know. Uh, Buddy Holly?
巴迪·霍利(1936-1959)美国最早的摇滚歌手之一
null
天哪  你以为我有多老
Jesus, uh, uh, how old do you think I am?
60岁左右吧
Maybe around 60.
真他妈让人郁闷
That's fucking depressing.
-对不起  -不用  不用
- I'm sorry. I... - No. No. No.
你说的心里话  没事  过来吧
You spoke your mind, it's all right. Come on in.
我给你带了点大麻
Well, I brought you some pot.
-不是吧  -没错
- No. - Yeah.
给你做了点布朗尼
I made you some brownies.
你真是太好了
That's very kind of you.
我欠你多少钱
How, uh, how much do I owe you?
我请客  要是你还想要
It's on the house. If you want more,
我们可以之后再说价格的事
we can talk prices later.
我靠  非常感谢
Fuck me. Thank you very much.
-不客气  -谢谢
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
介意我问个私人问题吗
You mind if I ask you something personal?
不  问吧
No, go ahead.
你和男的在一起过吗
Have you ever been with a man?
没  没有  没有  没有
No. Nope. Nope. Nope.
没有  真的没有
No, I can't say that I have.
你想操我吗
Would you like to fuck me?
那种
Like...
-操你屁股  -对
- in your ass? - Yeah.
-干净吗  -对  应该是干净的
- Is it... is it clean? - Yeah. I mean it should be.
不过  我也可以给你口一发
But no. I mean, I can always give you blowjob, too.
好吧  再给我倒一杯
Okay. Pour me another one of those
多倒一点  因为我
and make it very generous because I'm...
-当然  -真的不确定
- Of course. - ...really not sure how much
自己想记住多少
of this I'm gonna wanna remember.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以  没有什么  我是说  不会
So, like, there's no... I mean, couldn't...
我们不需要亲亲的  对吧
we don't have to kiss, right?
-没有亲亲  -没有
- There's no kissing. - No.
是因为我们都是男的吗
Is it like 'cause we're boys?
-对  -好吧
- Yeah. - Oh, okay.
我们齐聚在这里  共同见证
And so we're gathered to dedicate...
当代最杰出的艺术家之一的作品
the work of one of the finest contemporary artists of today,
一位我有幸称之为朋友的人
and someone that I am honored to call a dear friend,
-维罗妮卡·辛克莱·布朗夫人  -做得好
- Mrs. Veronica Sinclair Brown. - Well done.
-真是令人作呕  -很漂亮
- It's blatantly foul. - Beautiful.
挺美的
It's, uh, wonderful.
很好
Oh, that's great.
请问那是什么
May I ask what is it?
就是个大鸡巴
It's a giant schmeckle.
就这样
There you go.
-好极了  干得好  -说得好
- Excellent. Well done. - Hear, hear.
-很漂亮  -真好
- Beautiful. - This is lovely.
我们真的很欣赏这个作品
We appreciate it so much.
多谢前来  失陪一下
We're lucky to have you. Would you excuse me?
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
妈妈不允许我去州立学校
Um, mom says I'm not allowed to go to state schools.
你妈妈没权力不允许你做任何事
Your mom is not allowed to say you're not allowed.
你最好还是不要去
It's probably best if you don't.
别听他的  听我的
Don't listen to him. Listen to me.
精彩的作品  真的
Splendid work, truly.
-谢谢  彼得  -不用谢
- Thank you, Peter. - Yeah.
你觉得呢  奥丽芙
What do you think, Olive?
那个  是  挺棒的
The... uh, it was... yeah, it was good.
挺好的
It's all right, yeah.
要一起喝杯酒庆祝一下吗
So, shall we have a celebratory drink?
我很乐意  但亨利要带我去参加
I'd love to, but Henry has me going out to dinner
赞助商的酒宴
with the benefactors.
是一个康涅狄格州的老牌家族
It's an old money from Connecticut.
回家见
I'll see you two at home.
再见  亲爱的  谢谢  彼得
Bye, sweetie. Thanks, Peter.
你确定不要
Are you sure you don't want
来点伏特加或是布朗尼吗
a little splash of vodka or brownie?
你和妈妈为什么还在一起
Why are you and mom still together?
是的
Yeah.
真是个奇怪的问题
That's a rather odd question.
并不是
No, it's not.
我想你是对的  我们
And I guess you're right, we... um...
我想等你长大
I think as you get older,
你就会发现自己需要
you, um, find yourself needing someone
能让自己对生活负责的人
to hold accountable for life
而不是到头来发现只是自己的想象
not turning out exactly as you'd imagined it.
天哪  爸
Jesus, dad.
我知道
I know.
但听我说  不是所有感情都是这样
But listen to me, not every relationship has to be that.
我是说  话虽如此  大多数都是这样
I mean, having said that, most are.
好吧
Okay.
换个轻松点的话题  最近和泰勒怎么样
On that happy note. How's it going with Taylor?
进展很顺利
It's going really well.
是吗  好  那就好
Yeah? Good, that's good.
非常好
That's very good.
你爱上她了吗
Are you in love?
是的
Yeah. I am.
可以
No shit.
我真为你高兴  亲爱的
Yeah, well, I'm happy for you, sweetheart.
我真开心  真为你开心
I'm so happy. I'm so happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你要确保她明白你的价值
You make sure she understands your worth.
-我知道  她明白  -她最好明白
- I know. She does. - She better.
她妈的最好明白
She damn well better.
你女儿坠入爱河了
Your daughter is in love.
你有让她小心一点吗
Did you tell her to be careful?
没有
No.
我告诉她要享受
Told her to enjoy herself.
第三章
我真的要死了
实现自己的命运是一个人唯一的义务
To realize one's destiny is a person's only obligation.
于是他开始倾听沙漠
And so, he begins listening to the desert,
然后  发现这个世界的灵魂
and, discovering the soul of the world,
这不可避免地把我们带向
which then inevitably, leads us to...
好了  停
All right, stop.
你得了个B
You get a B.
-但我还没说完  -坐下
- But I'm not finished. - Take a seat.
我觉得挺不错的
I thought it was great.
我想问你们一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你们有从这门课上收获到什么吗
Are you guys getting anything out of this shit?
有
Yeah.
很好  因为我不得不说  我也有收获
Good. Because I have to say, I am as well.
你们都是群可靠的年轻人
I mean, you're all rather a solid group of young adults,
我很享受你们的陪伴
and I enjoy your company.
是的  没错  我觉得我们都很成熟
Yeah. Yeah, I'd say we're all pretty mature.
成熟这个词不过是
Well, maturity is really just another word for...
你咽下了多少痛苦的另一种说法
how much misery you'd swallow.
没错  正是如此
Yeah, totally.
我说的痛苦是别人给你带来的  萝丝
I'm talking about the piss and shit of others, Rose,
不是你自己的
not your own.
介意我抽根大麻烟吗
Do you mind if I smoke a joint?
谢谢
Thanks.
我很愿意帮忙  接手他的课
I'm more than happy to help, uh, pick up his classes,
如果这样能帮上忙的话
if that helps at all.
你这是在逗我吗
You got to be kidding me.
他是在抽大麻烟吗
Is he smoking a marijuana cigarette?
也许他只是试着
Look, maybe he's just trying to be...
真他妈难以置信
Fucking unbelievable.
理查德啊
Oh, Richard.
你为什么戴着墨镜
Why are you wearing sunglasses?
我得了癌症  我本就该在不常见的场合
I have cancer, I'm supposed to wear sunglasses
戴着墨镜
in unusual places.
行吧
Yeah.
不好意思  能再给我们来两杯吗
Excuse me, can we have two more please?
不用了  请结账吧
No, the check please.
为什么
Why?
听着  你得跟我走
Look, you're coming with me.
我不想跟你走
I don't wanna go with you.
彼得  我们要去哪儿
Peter, where are we going?
我要带你去互助小组
I'm taking you to support group.
什么互助小组
A support group for what?
-癌症  -天哪
- Cancer. - Oh, Jesus.
你要想让我帮你搞定学术休假的事情
Want me to help you with your sabbatical,
那就为了我去  这件事对我来说可不容易
then do this for me. This is not easy for me,
说实话  这件事真的很艰难
it's actually, it's quite hard.
我理解  但是  你要知道  是我要死
I understand that, but, you know, it's my death.
是啊
Yeah.
这是个什么玩意儿
What the fuck is this?
这辆车是芭芭拉的
Well, it's, it's Barbara's.
我才不要进去
I'm not getting in.
闭嘴  上车
Shut up, and get in the damn car.
其实这车开起来挺舒服的
It actually drives quite nice.
开下车门
Door.
-好了  -很好
- Here you go. - Well done.
都结婚20年了  我以为她会
After 20 years of marriage, I thought she'd, you know,
陪我到最后一刻
stick around until I died.
至少  我希望她能这样
At least, I hoped she would.
但我猜这样真的没意义吧
But, I guess, it was really no point,
我猜对她来说
you know, I guess it makes more sense for her
向前看才是最合理的
to move on now.
但尽管如此  我  我
But despite all that, I'm-I'm...
我感觉很好
I'm feeling pretty good.
我过得还行
I'm doing okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你跟我们分享你的战斗  艾德
Thank you for sharing the journey of your battle, Ed.
好的  准备好就开始说吧
All right. Whenever you're ready.
我叫彼得  我很健康
My name is Peter, I'm healthy,
我没得癌症
I don't have cancer,
至少我觉得自己没有
at least I don't think I do.
我的朋友
my friend,
理查德有癌症
Richard does.
我觉得他可以来这里聊聊这件事
And I thought that he could come here and talk about it.
我很
I'm...
害怕
scared,
我很担心
I'm worried,
我不想失去我最好的朋友
I don't wanna lose my best friend.
你这番话真的很有爱  彼得
That is really very lovely of you, Peter.
谢谢你跟我们分享你的
Thank you for sharing the journey of your...
战斗
battle.
好的  理查德
All right, Richard.
你准备好了就开始吧
Whenever you're ready.
不不不  我才不要搞这套  不不
Oh, no, no, no. I'm not doing this. No, no.
-拜托  -我没什么好说的
- Come on. - I have nothing to say.
-这对你有好处  -那好吧
- It's good for you. - Uh, well, um,
不如从你确诊开始说起吧
why don't you start with your diagnosis?
还是别了吧
I'd rather not,
我其实更想离开这里
I'd actually prefer to leave this place
因为这里灯光不好
because the lighting is poor down here,
闻起来还有一股小便蛋糕和小甜饼的味道
and it smells like urinal cakes and sugar cookies.
你会发现如果你
Well, you find that if you...
如果你从确诊开始说起
if you start with your diagnosis...
我觉得你会发现我早就知道
I think that you're gonna find that I already know
无论你要说什么  我都会提出反对
that I disagree with whatever you're about to say.
彼得  我们走吧  以后再试
Peter, let's go. We'll give it another shot.
有人想离开这里去喝一杯
Would anyone else like to go and grab a drink,
逃离这个负能量情感圈吗
and escape this emotional circle jerk?
你呢
What about you?
你也许需要来上一两杯
You might need a drink or two.
理查德  我有癌症
Richard, I... I've got cancer.
我也有啊
So do I.
死神将至  祝你们一切顺利
Well, best of luck with your impending deaths.
-好  你也是  -谢谢
- Yeah, you, too. - Thank you.
理查德  你得留下  我想帮你
Oh, Richard, you gotta stay. I wanna help you.
彼得  不要
Peter, no.
我要是死在这里  我的尸体
I'd die here, and my corpse
不过也就用来生生虫子而已
is nothing more than a breeding ground for ticks.
再说  这样的话
Plus, this way,
我还能一直领工资
I get to collect my salary until the bitter end.
或者还能领得更久  这就要看
Maybe even after, depending on
我的尸体多久会被发现了
how quickly it takes me to find, my, uh, body.
我必须离开
I have to leave for, uh...
为了奥丽维娅
for Olivia's sake.
别
No.
不不  拜托  听着
Oh, no, no, come on. Listen.
-好吧  -好  我要
- Uh, yeah. - All right. I'm gonna...
-我很抱歉  -我知道
- I am so sorry. - I know.
我的朋友
My friend.
理查德
Richard.
-听我说  -好
- Listen to me. - Yeah.
我觉得是时候去加拿大了
I think it's time to go up to Canada.
-不  我不  -嗯
- No. I don't... - Yeah.
彼得  人家都在议论我们了
Peter, you know they're talking about us.
你好  布朗教授
Hi. Hello, Professor Brown.
-你好  克莱尔  -你在这里干什么
- Hey, Claire. - What are you doing here?
-幸会  -幸会
- Nice to see you. - Nice to see you.
这位是  克莱尔
This is... Claire, uh...
这位是克莱尔  这位是彼得
This is Claire and this is Peter.
-你好  -幸会
- Hi. - Nice to see you.
事实上  她是亨利·莱特的侄女
She's, in fact, a niece of Henry Wright.
亨利  亨利  真好
Henry, Henry? Oh, how wonderful.
那很好  很高兴见到你
That's great, good to meet you.
你没必要这样  因为她也看不起他
You don't have to say that shit because she despises him
-就跟我们一样  -别这么说
- as much as we do. - Don't say things like that.
他很好  亨利·莱特
He's all right, Henry Wright.
他人挺好的
He's perfectly right.
我再要三杯酒  谢谢
I'll have another three please.
-不  我不想走  -不  你要
- No, I don't want go. - No, no, you're...
-我玩得很开心  -你在耍酒疯
- I'm having fun. - You're behaving like a troll.
我们要走了
We gotta go.
有人说过你很漂亮吗
Has anyone ever told you that you're beautiful?
谢谢你  彼得
Thank you, Peter.
好孩子
Good boy.
好了  就这样  好了  上车
Okay. That's it. Okay. Get in the car. Just get...
我能  请你喝杯睡前酒吗
Hey, can I, uh, buy you a nightcap?
睡前酒
Nightcap?
芭芭拉会杀了我的
Barbara's gonna kill me.
如果我说不  你会失望吗
Would you be disappointed if I said no?
这是一辆迷你库柏吗
Was it a Mini Cooper?
会的
Yes.
-晚安  彼得  -晚安
- Goodnight, Peter. - Night.
-理查德  -怎么
- Richard? - Yeah.
爱你
Love you.
我想告诉你  我非常敬佩你的勇敢
I'd like to say how much I admire your bravery.
怎么个勇敢法
Bravery for what?
勇敢做你自己
For being who you are,
还如此坚定不移
and doing so, unflinchingly.
那不是勇敢  那是冷漠
That's not bravery, that's apathy.
不是的
No, it's not.
我要去放点歌
I'm gonna go put on some music.
I Never Had No One By Sam The Sham & The Pharaohs
null
你还好吗
Are you all right?
不
No.
不  我不好
No, I'm not.
我得了癌症
I got cancer.
没关系  跟我年纪一样的人都得了癌症
It's all right. Everyone my age has cancer.
出于某种原因  它一直都没有发作
For some reason, it just never really kind of...
直到
hit until...
现在  我才知道它真正的含义
now, what it really means.
因为我要死了
You know, because I'm gonna die.
我真的要死了
I mean, I'm really gonna die.
我很抱歉  理查德
I'm sorry, Richard.
帮我个忙  别告诉其他人  好吗
Do me a favor, please keep that between us, yeah?
好的
Okay.
除了彼得  我只告诉过你
You're the only person I've ever told, outside of Peter.
甚至都还没告诉我老婆和女儿
Haven't even told my wife and daughter yet.
过来和我跳舞吧
Come dance with me.
跳舞
Dance?
我不跳舞
I don't dance.
那今晚跳一次
Dance tonight.
好吧
Okay.
我现在要怎么做
What do I do now?
就这样吗
Is this it?
好吧
Well, okay.
这么糟糕吗
Is this so bad?
没有
No.
没有  其实还挺好的
No, this is actually quite nice.
理查德
Richard?
Richard.
救命啊
Help.
Help!
老天  理查德
Oh, Jesus Christ, Richard.
发生了什么
What the hell happened?
我没事  冷静点  别
I'm all right, just calm down. Don't...
一切都好  我没事
Everything's fine, I'm all right.
我没死  我很好
I didn't die. I'm good.
这是谁
Well, who's that?
这是圣地亚哥
That's Santiago.
谁是圣地亚哥
Who's Santiago?
他是我的园丁
He's my gardener.
你园丁在这里干嘛
What's your gardener doing here?
他是我的紧急联络人
He's my emergency contact.
我的天  理查德
Christ, Richard
我们能私下谈谈吗
Um, can we have a word in private please?
不用  没关系  他不会说英语
No, that's fine, he doesn't speak any English.
看好了
Watch this.
圣地亚哥  今天星期几
Santiago, what day is it?
看见了吗  煎饼
See? Pancakes.
劳伦·巴考尔  犹太人  美国演员
null
是的  劳伦·巴考尔
Yes, Lauren Bacall.
说吧  你想说什么  没事的
Talk. What are you gonna say? It's fine.
理查德  你必须要改过自新了
Richard, you've got to clean up your act.
是的  我搞砸了  我会少吃点"糖"
Yeah. I fucked up. I'll slow down the candy,
多吃点绿色的  好吗
and I'll go green for a bit, okay?
-卖草吗  -大麻  也算草
- Selling grass? - Marijuana, yeah.
你从哪搞来的
Oh, and where are you getting it?
我的一个学生  他叫丹尼
Student of mine. His name is Danny.
是个好孩子  非常非常非常聪明的孩子
Really good kid, very, very, very smart kid.
听着  我不想让你因为嗑药过量
Look, I don't want you dying over something
这种幼稚的行为死去  好吗
as infantile as an overdose, okay?
我要走了
I'm gonna go out.
你会在医院里染上什么病的
Oh, or you'll catch something in the hospital.
好吧  我们学校见
Oh, okay. Well, I'll see you back on, uh, on the campus.
好的
Yeah.
我们学校见
I'll see you back on campus.
你说过了  走吧  彼得  谢谢你来看我
Yeah, you said, just go, Pete. Thanks for coming by.
你气色不错  气色不错
Yeah, you're looking good, you're looking good.
我看起来病怏怏的吗
Do I look sick to you?
你现在躺在病床上  理查德
You're in a hospital bed, Richard.
你不说说昨晚去哪了吗
You wanna say where you were last night?
不是很想
Not really.
我们说好了的  为了奥丽维娅
We had a deal for Olivia.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好  只是背疼
Yeah. It's just my back.
理查德
Richard?
请说
Yes?
抱歉  我没听见你回复
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't hear you answer.
我是卡罗尔  亨利的秘书
Uh, it's Carol, Henry's secretary.
理查德  亨利想和你谈谈
Uh, Richard, Henry would like to have a word with you.
-什么时候  -现在
- When? - Now.
告诉他我很忙
Tell him I'm busy.
他说这件事相当紧急
He says the matter is rather urgent.
告诉他我忙一件很紧急的事
Tell him I'm urgently busy.
理查德
Richard.
请说
Yes?
他准备好见你了
He's ready to see you now.
告诉我  理查德  你喜欢鱼吗
Tell me, Richard, do you like fish?
不  我有时会吃鱼
No. I mean to eat sometimes,
但除此之外  不  我不喜欢
but outside of that, no. No, I don't.
我相信人类可以从鱼身上学到很多
I believe men could learn a lot from fish.
这是我听过最愚蠢的话了
That's the most asinine thing I've ever heard.
我们不如直接进入正题吧
Why don't we just cut to the chase?
好吧
All right.
我们需要谈一些针对你的指控
We need to talk about certain allegations
这些指控已经引起了我的关注
that have come to my attention,
其中一些还很严重
some of which are serious.
你可闭嘴吧
Don't even start.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我知道你听到了我的话
I know you heard what I said.
你这么问是为了做做样子
You're simply saying that for effect.
你想让我重复自己的话  我不会重复
You want me to repeat myself, I won't.
我可是这所大学的校长
I am chancellor of this university.
我他妈一点都不在乎
I couldn't give a fucking rat's balls
你他妈是谁  我拥有终身教职
who the fuck you are. I have tenure,
此外
and furthermore,
你根本没有资格或是权力对我指手划脚
you're in no position of power when it comes to the two of us.
你背着妻子在外面偷情  亨利
You're cheating on your wife, Henry.
你出轨了  还不是一般的出轨
You're having an affair, and not just any affair,
而是和一位忠心耿耿的教职工的妻子
but one with a wife of a devoted faculty member,
具体地说
specifically
我的妻子
mine.
不止如此  你还从不断减少的预算中
Not only that. But you've allocated funds
拨出资金来建造花岗岩大鸡巴
from a dwindling budget for granite erections
搞得满校园都不堪入目
that you just littered throughout this entire campus.
而奇怪的是  设计这些东西的
And oddly enough, they come from the woman
正是你背地里偷情的对象
that you're bird dogging on the side.
可否提醒我一下
Can you remind me
维罗妮卡的作品每件卖出了多少钱
how much does one of Veronica's works go for?
校长  你就像只奔跑的雄鹿一样
Chancellor, I have mounted you
被我骑在身下
like a running stag,
而且我已经开搞你了
and I am pumping away at you,
就像个野蛮人
like a savage,
你明白的
and you know it.
那么现在
Now,
我就默认我的学术休假申请
I'm gonna take it that my request for sabbatical
已经被批准了
has been accepted.
第四章
真的开始发作了
别摆出这么热衷的样子
Don't look so enthusiastic.
为什么
Why would I?
一方面  酒席菜品是别家承办的
Well, for one, it's gonna be catered.
而且芭芭拉只会讲她去过多少地方旅游
All Barbara ever talks about is how well traveled she is.
她还能说什么
Well, what else would she talk about?
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
西班牙伊维萨岛的空气
The air in Ibiza,
真的无与伦比
there's really nothing like it.
光是想想  我就激动到视线模糊
I'm getting misty, just thinking about it.
彼得  让我们的经理人
Peter, put our agent
跟他们保持联系  好吗
in touch with them, all right?
好的  当然  我很愿意效劳
Yes, of course, yes, I'd be happy to.
理查德
Richard?
理查德  你怎么了
Richard, what's the matter?
亲爱的  随他去吧
Uh, darling, let him be.
总之  话说回来  伊维萨岛
Anyway, as I was saying, Ibiza...
你还好吗
Are you all right?
-你不会后悔的  -我岂止还好
- You won't regret it. - I'm more than all right.
-不可能后悔  -我状态完美
- You can't. - I'm perfect.
除非你疯了才会后悔
I mean, unless you're mad.
我说得对吧  彼得
Am I right or what, Peter?
你说得对  亲爱的  你都对
Oh, you're right, darling, you're right.
还有哪位的鱼肉里有刺吗
Does anybody else have bones in the fish?
我们有值得庆祝的事了
We have something to celebrate.
什么事  你也得癌症了吗
What's that? You got cancer, too?
不  我没有  你为什么总是说这个
No. I do not. Why do you keep saying that?
我的
Uh, my...
我的囊肿倒是挺疼的
Uh, I... my cyst is rather sore.
你嗓子里长了东西吗
Something in your throat?
我觉得应该去检查一下
I think I should get it screened.
-或许吧  -好了  好
- Maybe. - Yeah. Yeah.
-摩洛哥  -没错
- Morocco. - Yeah.
理查德  不  别这样  不行
Uh, Richard, uh, no, no, no,
那样只会助长她的威风
that'll only encourage her.
我们发现  每次去的时候
...We've noticed that it's allowed us
它都会让我们发现关于我们自身的新东西
every time we've been to discover something new about ourselves.
你  我的朋友  已被奖励学术休假
You, my friend, have been awarded a sabbatical.
谢谢
Thank you.
亨利·莱特上周刚签了文件批准
Henry Wright signed the paperwork, only last week.
-抱歉失陪  -瞧  我跟你说过
- Excuse me. - See, I told you.
你们两个在做什么
What are you two doing?
我们在谈工作  仅此而已
Uh we're discussing work. That's all.
彼得  今天是我生日
Peter, it's my birthday,
你们下次再谈  来加入我们
save it for another time, and come mingle.
-好  -还有  别关门
- All right. - And don't close these doors.
好的  亲爱的
No, darling.
总之  彼得吓坏了
Anyway, Peter was petrified...
我们到底为什么要结婚
Why the hell did we ever get married?
你还好吗
You okay?
还好  我没事  亲爱的
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine, babe.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
嗯
Yeah.
是啊  我会没事的
Yeah. I'm gonna be fine.
我们最初爱上的人
The person one loves at first
并不会是到头来爱着的那个
is not the person one loves at last.
爱不是最后的目标
Love is not an end,
而是一个过程  人类在这个过程中尝试着
it's a process through, which one person attempts
了解彼此
to know another.
没了
That's it.
一个词概括
And in a word?
两个词概括  谜之简单
In two words, deceptively simple.
讲得非常好
Beautifully, beautifully executed.
用一些能点醒我们的东西
And it's a really nice way to
来结束这门课
end the class with a little,
真是再好不过了
kick in the ass.
所以  你拿了A
So, you get an A.
-谢谢你  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
我估计其他人都在等着我
And I suppose the rest of you are waiting
吐出几句深刻的智慧之言
for me to vomit out some profound words of wisdom.
差不多
Yeah, kind of.
还以为你们不会问了呢
Oh, thought you'd never ask.
来拉我一把
Come here, give me a hand.
谢了
Thanks.
好
Okay.
听着
Listen...
这个世界需要你们这样的人
The world needs people like you.
说真的  这世界渴求你们这种人才
The world is literally dying for your kind.
拥抱你们的责任  做到亲力亲为
Embrace that responsibility, and you run with it.
出去挣一份相配的报酬  回馈这个世界
Get out there, earn your keep. Give back.
这不会容易  从来都没有容易事
It's not gonna be easy. Never gonna be easy.
很多时候  你们都会是孤身一人
For much of it, you'll stand alone
但你们一定要坚守立场
but you've got to stand strong.
真的  我恳求你们
You know, I beg you
永远不要甘于平庸
to not give into mediocrity,
别像另外那百分之98的人一样
like the other 98 percent of the world.
因为那样的话  你们等于是对自己
Because you would be doing yourselves,
也是对这世界  帮了个大倒忙
and the world, a greatest disservice.
你们都太聪明
You're all too smart.
别让如此的聪明才智白白浪费
You're too smart to let it go to waste.
而且你们这辈子只能活一次
And you've got one shot at this.
只能他妈的活一次
One fucking shot.
哪怕一分钟都别让它白白流逝
Don't let a moment of it slip by.
抓住时间  抓紧生命  创造自己的生活
Grab it, snatch it up, make it yours.
庆祝每一个微小的时刻
Celebrate every moment.
庆祝每一次呼吸
Celebrate every fucking breath.
我跟你们说
I'm telling you,
人生就是转瞬即逝的鸟鸣
life, it's a birdsong.
就这些了吗
Was that it?
嗯  我觉得是吧  没错
Yeah, I think... I think so, yeah.
没错  就这些
Yeah, that's it.
理查德  理查德
Richard? Richard.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
不  不要  理查德  你还好吗
Oh, no, no, no. Richard, are you all right?
天啊
Christ.
-天使  -什么
- Angels. - What?
我听见了天使的声音  彼得  他们在歌唱
I hear the angels, Peter, they're singing.
无伴奏合唱团  起源于中世纪教会音乐
null
不  那是阿卡贝拉社团  理查德
No, that's the... that's the acapella group, Richard.
来
Here.
什么  我们哪来的阿卡贝拉社团
Why? Why do we have an acapella group?
我们一直都有阿卡贝拉社团
We've always had an acapella group.
去他们的吧  你能带我去教堂吗
Well, fuck them. Can you take me to the bells?
-什么  -我想看看钟
- What? - I wanna see the bells.
-钟  -对
- The bells? - Yeah.
好  没问题  来吧
All right. All right. Come.
我先给你弄点水喝
I'll get you some water first.
彼得
Peter,
这里其他能坐的位置还有很多
there are a lot of other good places to sit in here.
好吧
Yes.
当然
Of course.
谢了
Yeah.
你感觉到什么了吗
Can you feel anything?
没有
No.
但我很喜欢这里的灯光
But I enjoy the lighting.
-你呢  -不
- You? - No.
但没关系
But that's all right.
圣母保佑  帮帮我的朋友
Please mother of God, help my friend...
恐怕要开始发作了
Afraid it's starting to kick in.
痛吗
Does it hurt?
当然
Oh, fuck yeah.
我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
我能忍受
I'll manage.
没事  彼得  该来的总会来
It's fine, Peter. We knew this was coming.
是啊
Yeah.
我回首过往
I mean, uh, I look back on everything,
一切都变得合理了
and it all somehow makes so much sense.
就好像  也不会有其他的结局
It's as though, uh, it couldn't be any other way.
我们的灵魂为何如此残破
Why's our soul broken?
荒诞
Absurd.
但
Yet...
却又是完美的
It's perfect.
当你仔细审视它  它又是如此完美
And it's also perfect when you look at it.
-你明白我的意思吗  -明白
- You know what I mean? - Yeah.
很难离开这里
It's gonna be hard to leave this place.
很难说再见
It's gonna be hard to say goodbye.
理查德  我会想你的
Richard, I'm gonna miss you.
我也会想你的  彼得  如果我可以的话
I'm gonna miss you too, Peter. If I'm able.
妈的  我要哭了
Fuck, I'm going to cry.
-不  -天哪
- No. - Dear God.
拜托了
Please.
请不要这样  不  不  不哭
Please don't do this. No, no, shh.
-该死  -不  不  不  听着
- Dammit. - No, no, no. Listen.
我真的希望你不要哭
I really prefer if you didn't cry.
听我说  我们尽力了
Listen to me. We tried.
-对  对  -现在我们走吧  好了
- Yes. Yes. - Now let's go. Come on.
-来吧  -好的
- Come on. - Okay.
-对不起  -走吧
- I'm sorry. - Come on.
没事的
It's all right.
来吧  彼得
Come on, Peter.
你是个好人  理查德
You're a good man, Richard.
你也是  我的朋友
So are you, my friend.
谢谢你对我这么好
Thank you for being so good to me.
我在努力  理查德  我在努力
I'm trying, Richard. I'm trying.
这种感觉竟如此自然
Isn't it strange how natural this feels?
-是啊  -两个男人
- Yeah. - Two men,
在教堂里热情地互相拥抱
holding one another, passionately, in a church.
自由地互相抚摸
Groping one another freely.
是啊
Yeah.
-你好傻  -好了  变态
- You're stupid. - Come on you, pervert.
拜
Bye.
你今晚要出去吗
You're going out tonight?
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
玩得开心点  好吗
You have fun, okay?
嗯  你也是
Yeah, you, too.
我觉得不太可能
I'm not sure that's possible,
不过我跟你保证  我们会尽力的
but I'm promising you that we will try.
去玩吧  孩子
Go get 'em, kid.
拜  爸爸
Bye, dad.
第五章
我还有话想说
真的非常感谢你的到来
Thank you so much for coming, really.
你真是一年比一年漂亮
You get just lovelier every year.
维罗妮卡  理查德  我们的贵客
Veronica, Richard. Our guest of honor.
你能来真好
So nice you could make it.
我们无论如何都不会错过的
We wouldn't miss it for the world.
你好  我是理查德
How do you do? Hi, I'm Richard.
好吧
Okay.
你这招呼打得可真够热情
That's a hell of a greeting.
我要去吧台了
I'm going to the bar.
彼得和我决定今年留在国内
Peter and I have decided to stay in this year,
在迈阿密过圣诞节
and spend Christmas in Miami.
真好
How fashionable.
唐纳  我的生日聚会你没来  为什么
Donna, you weren't at my birthday party. Why?
我一直都想告诉你
I've been so wanting to tell you
我搞错日期了
that I mixed up the date.
打扰一下  请大家注意一下
Excuse me everyone, if I could have your attention.
晚餐马上开始
Dinner is to be served shortly,
所以  请各位
so, if you would be so kind
移步到餐厅
as to begin migrating to the dining room,
感谢大家的配合
that would be much appreciated.
维罗妮卡  你坐我旁边
Veronica. You'll be right here next to me.
理查德
Richard.
不  不  不  恐怕位置有限
No, no, no. tight quarters, I'm afraid.
他坐后面哪里
He'll be somewhere in the back.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
不好意思  理查德怎么不坐在这桌
Sorry, why isn't Richard sitting at this table?
我可以向你保证  我们在座位安排上
I can assure you that there has been a great deal of thought
进行了很多的考虑
that's going into the seating arrangements.
什么
What?
死了  没了
Dead, gone.
太可怕了  怎么死的
That's horrible. What was it?
恐怕是黑色素瘤
Melanoma, I'm afraid.
欢迎入座  年轻人
Welcome, young man.
家人呢
And the families?
说真的
Honestly,
-你还是不知道为好  -真的吗
- you don't wanna know. - Really?
趁着上菜的时间
While everyone's being served,
我想说两句
I just wanted to say a couple words.
代表我自己和我美丽的妻子  欢迎诸位
On behalf of both myself and my lovely wife, welcome.
很荣幸邀请到今晚在座的每一位
It's an honor to have each and every one of you here tonight.
我们大家有目共睹
Now, I know I'm not alone
这可能是我们有史以来最好的学季
when I say that this quarter may have been our very best.
而作为你们的领导以及校长
And the opportunity to serve,
能有机会为大家服务
as your president and chancellor,
一直让我倍感谦卑
has been nothing short of humbling.
所以谢谢大家
So thank you.
我只希望
I can only hope
大家能继续追求更高远的目标
to live up to the high standards that you have set.
-我们会的  -干杯
- We will. - Cheers.
现在  趁夜未央享受晚餐吧
Now, let us eat for the night is young.
讲得真好
That was a lovely speech.
好极了
Beautiful.
你们不会真信了他那堆屁话吧
Did you actually buy that shit, really?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你是传媒系的吗
Are you in the communications department?
我有话想说
I have something that I would like to say.
你能别弹了吗
Could you stop playing that
不然我就要把这刀扔过去了
before I heave this knife in your direction?
谢谢
Thank you.
拿酒的小姐
Young lady with the wine,
不介意的话可以站在我旁边不要离开吗
would you mind just standing right by my side, and never leave?
因为我有很多话要说
Because I have much to say
-还有很多杯酒要敬  -我的上帝
- and many to toast. - Oh, my God.
那些还不认识我的人  我叫理查德·布朗
Those of you who do not know, my name is Richard Brown.
英文教授
Professor of English.
为我干杯
Cheers to me.
干杯
Cheers.
-干杯  -敬理查德
- Cheers. - To Richard.
亨利·莱特  我代表在座的每个人
Henry Wright, on behalf of every one of us here,
为这强迫前来的美好夜晚
let me, please, express our gratitude,
-向你表示感谢  -抱歉
- for this finely forced evening. - I'm sorry.
你对学生
The commitment that you have shown
教职工
to the students, faculty,
甚至教职工的妻子  所表现出的承诺
even the wives of the faculty...
令人印象深刻
...is very, very impressive.
你已经超越了自己
You've outdone yourself.
行胜于言
And it shows.
就我而言  三个蛋
As far as I'm concerned, three balls...
-值得三次干杯  -不要
- deserves three cheers. - No.
好了  理查德  差不多得了
All right, Richard, I think that's enough.
亨利  我说话的时候不要打断我
Henry, do not interrupt me while I'm talking.
尤其是在这么多人面前
Particularly in front of so many people.
-你明白吗  -不  我不明白
- Do you understand? - No, I don't understand.
-没错  -没人能有三个睾丸
- Yeah. - Nobody has three testicles.
敬彼得·马修
To Peter Matthew.
都别说了
Gotta shut up.
你真是有一颗金子般的心
Your heart is truly one of gold.
-没错  -这所大学非常荣幸
- It is. - And this college is...
-能拥有你这样的人  -是的
- very lucky to have you. - That's true.
当然  还要感谢你的辛苦工作
Of course, thank you for your hard work.
但最重要的是
But most important,
谢谢你这样一位真诚的朋友
thank you for being a true friend.
-敬彼得  干杯  -干杯
- To Peter, cheers. - Cheers.
除此之外  我感觉我还欠你们几句离别赠言
Also there are some parting words that I feel like I owe.
因为这将是我最后一次见到你们
Because this will be the last time that I ever see any of you.
不仅是因为我被奖励了学术休假
For not only have I been awarded a sabbatical,
好怪异  彼得
This is strange, Peter.
我要死了
...I'm gonna die.
没错
Yeah...
我要死了
I'm gonna die,
而且我要死得比我想象的要早得多
and I'm gonna die much sooner than I had imagined.
天哪
Oh, my goodness.
我知道  亲爱的
I know, dear.
他在说什么
What is he talking about?
所以在准备面对死亡的过程中
So in preparing for what lies ahead,
我开始意识到我这辈子大部分的时间里
I've come to realize that for much of my life,
我都被错付了
I've been mistaken,
我还失败了
and I failed.
我不仅没能领悟生命是有限的
I failed, not only to comprehend my mortality,
还没能珍惜它
but I've failed to appreciate it.
因此
And as a result,
我没能充分利用自己的生命
I've failed to make the most of my life.
维罗妮卡  你是个厉害的角色
Veronica, you're one hell of a sport.
你是个非常值得尊敬的对手
You are a very worthy adversary.
我很骄傲
Proud...
自己能够把你称作我的妻子
to have been able to call you my wife.
因为如果没有你  生活将会
Because life without you would've been,
黯淡无光
far less rich.
为此  我感谢你
And for that, I thank you.
无论如何
For whatever it's worth...
我爱你
I love you...
非常爱
deeply.
我知道
I know.
我们背叛了自己肩负的最重要的责任
We've turned our backs on the most important duty that we possess,
那就是过上我们自己选择的
to live a life that is rich in experience
精彩丰富的一生
that's of our own independent choosing.
抓住自己的时间  各位
Seize your fucking existence, folks.
为什么不让死神做我们最亲密的伙伴
Why don't we make death our closest fucking companion,
这样我们才终于有那么一秒
so that we can finally have a second,
有那么一毫秒来享受
a millisecond to appreciate
我们剩下的那点时间
that little bit of time that we have left.
最重要的是
And most important of all,
让我们活得痛快
let us live well,
这样我们才能死得痛快
so that we may fucking die well,
因为我们从未像此刻这样
because we've never been so close to death
如此接近死亡
than this very moment.
干杯
Cheers.
该死的  理查德  那可是水晶做的
Dammit, Richard. Those are crystal.
第六章
道别时刻
很抱歉让你以这种方式知道真相
I'm so sorry that you had to find out like that,
我只是不知道
and I just didn't...
我真的不知道该怎么告诉你
I mean, I honestly didn't know how to tell you.
我很害怕
I was scared.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我打算离开  亲爱的
I'm gonna leave, sweetheart.
我就是这么打算的
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
拜托了  努力去追寻幸福
Please, try and find some happiness.
我在努力
I'm working on it.
我知道你会找到的
I know you will.
再见  理查德
Goodbye, Richard.
再见  维罗妮卡
Goodbye, Veronica.
拜
Bye.
奥丽维娅
Olivia?
你怎么回来了  宝贝
What are you doing home, baby?
泰勒跟我分手了
Taylor broke up with me.
什么
What?
她把我甩了跟奈森·朗宁斯在一起了
She cheated on me with Nathan Runnings.
朗宁斯教授的孩子
Professor Runnings' kid?
听着
Listen.
好了  宝贝  过来
Come on, babe. Come here.
过来
Come here.
不用担心  亲爱的  你会没事的
Don't worry, sweetheart. You're gonna be fine.
这世界上有很多女人
The world's full of women
都在寻找自己的另一半
looking for someone to love.
会有一个人值得你去爱
There's gotta be somebody who deserves you.
你想喝点什么
What'll you have?
随便吧
I don't care.
男人失去女人的时候
Well, when a man loses a woman,
通常  他会喝威士忌
it's, typically whiskey he drinks.
所以
So,
我就推测
I'm kind of assuming that,
同性恋也会这样
a lesbian would do the same.
敬你的未来
Here's to your future.
敬你无比光明的未来
To your bright, bright future.
敬下地狱的泰勒
To Taylor rotting in hell.
没错  敬下地狱的泰勒
And yes, to Taylor rotting in hell.
干杯
Cheers.
我真的好为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
为什么
Why?
因为你拥有着
Because you possess everything
一个父亲能期望自己的女儿所能拥有的一切
that a father could ever want in a daughter, and more.
甚至更多
So much more.
爸爸
Dad.
怎么了  宝贝
Yeah, baby?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我病了  奥丽维娅
I'm sick, Olivia.
我病了
I'm sick.
你还会好起来吗
Are you gonna be okay?
不会了
No.
没事的
It's all right.
你会没事的  听见了吗
You're gonna be all right. Do you hear me?
你会很棒的
You're gonna be great.
我要离开一段时间
I'm gonna need to go away for a little bit.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我也不知道
I don't really know.
我只是有些事想在路上弄明白
I just got some things I gotta figure out.
我非常爱你  我的女儿
I love you so much, my girl.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你要继续走自己的这条路
You stay on this path of yours.
听见了吗
You hear me?
你要继续走这条属于自己的路
You stay on this path that's yours.
你做得很对  孩子
You're doing it right, kid.
我会非常想你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
我爱你
I love you.
吉宝
Jibbles,
咱们上路吧
let's hit the road.
来  吉宝
Here, Jibbles.
好孩子
Good boy.
你要确保让你妈妈照顾好你
You make sure your mom takes good care of you, huh?
我能照顾好我自己
I can take care of myself.
我毫不怀疑  孩子
I have no doubt about that, kid.
抱歉  吉宝
I'm sorry, Jibbles.
Little Things by Kathy Ingraham
null
献给贝蒂·苏·德普
献给哈莱姆·琼斯及杜克·里根
null